CAREER PROFILE

A meticulous and process-driven designer with experience in designing, improving processes, and recommending results-based solutions. Establishes trust, develops relationships and networks, and ensures a high degree of accuracy in all work. Proficient in numerous software design tools and three-dimensional modeling, showcasing expertise with complex projects and designs.

SKILLS

- Concept Ideation
- Human experience design
- Research and Presentation
- Content Layering and Critical Analysis
- Strategic Planning
- Visual Communication
- Root Cause Analysis
- Forward procurement planning
- Supply chain management
- Vendor Management

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- CAD software Autodesk Revit, AutoCAD, ArchiCAD, BIM
- 3D MODELLING Sketchup, Rhinoceros, Solid works
- Free hand sketching
- Management Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Project management
- Prototyping Hand-made Models, Laser-cut models, 3D prototypes
- Rendering Engine Twin Motion, V Ray
- Graphics Photoshop, Illustrator, CorelDraw

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ARCHITECT + LANDSCAPE ARCHITECT

JULY 2020 - AUGUST 2021

Gajra Infra Pvt.Ltd, Nashik.

- Working on schematic and construction design using AutoCAD, Adobe software and 3D software.
- Site analysis and code compliance for LIG and MIG housing projects of 392040 sq. ft in Nashik region.
- Construction drawing and site coordination of Industrial shed of 70,000 sq. ft area.
- Landscape design of garden for clubhouse and housing projects.
- Conducting budgetary, schematic and schedule analysis, and drawing review for the site base build and fit out program to manage client expectations while maintaining the design integrity of the architecture.
- Client presentation, Planning and managing the project timeline.

LANDSCAPE DESIGN INTERN

MAY 2019 - JULY 2019

Origin Architects, Nashik.

- Concept development, Client requirements and experiential design according to requirements.
- Worked on designing and making working drawings for a farmhouse.
- Managing the site and junior staff team on the site.
- Made technical drawings like lighting plan, planting plan, irrigation plan, management plan.

ARCHITECT

MAY 2018 – SEPTEMBER 2018

Gajra Infra Pvt.Ltd, Nashik.

- Worked on government project for construction of Toll Plaza at Hyderabad and Dhule.
- Supplied working and technical drawing to the sites.
- Costing and Estimation.

Ar. Umesh Bagul, Nashik.

- Worked on making of Municipal drawings and plan sanctioning.
- Basic Architectural drawings.
- Scheduling client meeting and making presentation for the meetings.

TRAINEE APRIL 2015 – JUNE 2015

Ar. Sagar Kabre Patil

- Learning about functioning of architect's office.
- Handling of basic concept development drawings.
- Model making and deriving alternatives with different materials.

EDUCATION

Master's in Construction Project Management

2021- PRESENT

Worcester Polytechnic Institute, Worcester

Courses Fall 2021

- MIS User Experience Design
- CE 580 Advanced Project Management
- CE 587 Building Information Modeling (BIM)

Master's in landscape architecture

2018 - 2020

Dr. Bhanuben Nanavati College of Architecture, Pune

Thesis – Landscape Development for a Grape Farm Cluster in Niphad Region, Maharashtra.

- Landscape architect perspective towards Agriculture.
- Current farming practices in the region and factors affecting the growth of plants and soil contamination.
- Design solutions to mitigate the current crisis in farming.
- Management plan and calendar for next 13 years.

Bachelor of Architecture 2013 - 2018

Dr. Bhanuben Nanavati College of Architecture, Pune

Thesis – "Aashray" – Old Age Home and Orphanage

- The purpose of the design was to create an environment where orphaned children and old people are able to enjoy living conditions as close as possible to normal life.
- A climate responsive and sustainable design program.
- A concept of family-based care living

CERTIFICATIONS / WORKSHOPS

- 1. Registered Architect at Council of Architecture, India.
- 2. Indian Society of Landscape Architecture.
- 3. Society of Ecological Restoration Foundation Training Programme in Practice of Ecological Restoration